>> 凯尔: 我们谈到了职能范围界定，
&gt;&gt; Kyle: We've talked
about function scoping,
现在我们转移注意力去阻止范围界定
let's shift our attention
now to block scoping.
像它听起来一样
Block scoping like it sounds,
它的作用是使用块中的花括号而不是函数来进行。
it's scoping that's done with blocks aka
curly braces instead of with functions.
同样的原则也要适用
Same principle is gonna apply.
我们想把东西放在一个街区里而不是包围
We wanna put something inside of a block
instead of inside of the enclosing
因为我们想把它藏起来所以名字碰撞的机会就更少了
scope because we wanna hide it, so that
it has fewer chances of name collision.
我们想保护一个细节保护未来的重构
We wanna protect a detail,
protect future refactoring,
这个道理都是一样的。
all the same principle applies.
只是我们现在使用的机制是块范围声明而不是
It's just the mechanism we use is now
a block scope declaration instead of
例如， IIFE 。
an IIFE, for example.
所以，让我们用一块方块来写，而不是写 IIFE 。
So Instead of writing an IIFE,
let's write it with a block.
您可以将该示例与该示例之间的差异进行比较
And you can compare mentally
the difference between that example with
一个 IIFE 或仅使用一个卷曲的括号，并使用一个类似的语句
an IIFE or just using a curly braced
block and using a let statement like
块作用域装饰， >> 凯尔: 它很轻
a block scope decoration,
&gt;&gt; Kyle: It's a lot lighter
体重不是吗?
weight isn't it?.
它也没有什么副作用，没有重新定义任何关于
It also has less side effects in the sense
it doesn't redefined anything about
返回或中断，或者任何其他的内容，所以块更容易
returns or breaks or any of that other
stuff, so blocks are a bit easier and
更轻的放进去的重量
lighter weight to put into places.
不是表情，所以
They're not expressions, so
不能在可以使用表达式的位置使用它们。
you can't use them in places
where you can use expressions.
但如果你把它们放在一个声明里，那就完全可以了。
But if you have them in a place that's
a statement, it's totally okay.
有时候更喜欢做这么轻的重量形式
And sometimes often a lot more preferable
to just do this lighter weight form,
围绕着一些东西
wrap a curly brace pair
around something and
在其中进行块作用域声明。
make a block scope
declaration inside of it.
现在你不能在这里做个变量因为历史上的
Now you can't just do a var here
because historically vars have been
将自身附加到外部函数作用域或全局作用域。
attaching themselves to the outer
function scope or global scope.
所以这里的 var 会把它自身附着在外域而不是卷曲的
So a var here would have attached itself
to the outer scope rather than the curly
花括号对。
brace pair.
>> 凯尔: 不破坏旧的旧代码或旧的旧代码，
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Instead of breaking old
backward or old previous code,
他们决定增加新的申报表格
they decided to add new declaration forms.
这就是我们从哪里得到的
So it's where we get the let and
the const from.
让你和康斯特这样做你可以在一个街区里发表声明
Let and const are so that you can make
a declaration inside of a block and
把那个街区变成了一个范围
it turns that block into a scope.
在它们有一个或多个内部的位置之前，这些块才是作用域。
Blocks are not scopes until they have
a let or const inside of them and
那么这种暗示就会使他们成为一个范围。
then that sort of implicitly
makes them a scope.
那是人们的关键所在
That's a key place where
people sort of get,
他们认为所有花括号都是范围，不是所有范围。
they think that all curly braces
are scopes, and they're not all scopes.
如果里面有一个或一个常量，它们只是一个范围。
They're only a scope if there's a let or
a const inside of it.
好，所以这是一个很轻的方式来做这个特定的例子。
Okay, so this was a lightweight way
of doing this particular example.
但在事情的更大范围内，范围界定的范围是怎样的呢 ?
But where does block scoping fit
in the larger scope of things?
我要声明你应该做的事情
I'm gonna make the claim that what you
should be doing with block scoping
正在使用类似的关键字来加强
is using something like
the let keyword to reinforce
你就会很自然地向你的读者发出信号
something that you would have already
naturally wanted to signal to your reader.
举个例子。
Here's an example.
如果您正在编写代码，如果您有一个需要临时的语句
If you were writing code where you had
an if statement that needed a temporary
变量用于执行某些操作，在此情况下要交换两个值。
variable to do something,
in this case to swap two values.
你给它打了个电话给读者
And you called it tmp to
signal to the reader,
只是暂时的占位符我不太想用它
it's just a temporary placeholder,
I'm not really using it for much.
我一定要把他的王牌放进去因为我想说
And definitely, I put the var tmp inside
of the if because I'm trying to say to
读者，您无需访问此文件或在任何其他地方使用此信息。
the reader, you don't need to access
this or use this anywhere else.
我们知道， var 的行为方式是它会将自身附加到
We know that the way var behaves
is that it'll attach itself to
蓝镜对吧
the blue scope, right?
它会是一个蓝色的大理石
It'll be a blue marble attached
to the whole function if.
但我们在暗示些什么
But we're signaling
something stylistically,
在语义上向读者说明此变量属于 if 语句。
semantically to the reader which is to say
this variable belongs to the if statement.
如果你这样做有些人也许会把你的 vars 放进去
If you do stuff like this, and some of
you may have put your vars inside of if
语句或其他类型的块之前或
statements or
other sorts of blocks before or
也许你把你的 var 语句放进去循环
maybe you put your var
statements inside of for loops.
这是很普通的事情。
That's a very common thing.
如果你做到了那你已经发信号了
If you've done that,
then what you were already signalling was,
不管你意识到与否，嘿读者，这是一个区块范围的变量。
whether you realized it or not, hey
reader, this is a block scoped variable.
现在我们有了一个街区范围的声明你可以安全地
And now that we have a block scope
declaration, you can safely replace those
现在你在强制执行你已经很有造型的信号了
and now you are enforcing the thing that
you were already stylistically signalling.
我认为这才是解决这个问题的适当方式
That I think is the appropriate way to
approach this feature which is to say,
你应该把它放在已经很明显，正确设计的地方
you should use it in places where it is
already obvious and correct design for
你要封锁范围
you to block scope something.
我不认为你应该去找机会
I do not think that you should go
looking for opportunities to more
通过多块作用域限定来完成代码
complexify your code by
having more block scoping for
没有特定的原因，因此您可以使用此热门的新 let 关键字。
no particular reason, just so
you can use this hot new let keyword.
你应该把它用在已经有阻碍作用的地方，好吗 ?
You should use it in places where it
already makes sense to block scope, okay?
那是我第一次想在你的
So that's the first shift
that I wanna have in your
思想是想把它作为替代
mental thinking is to think
about that as a replacement for
已在语义上发送的块作用域。
your already semantically
signalled block scope.
我不是一个大影迷因为我被劫持的方式
I'm not a big fan by the way of
this hijacking of scopes because I
通常认为一个 if 语句只是一个 if 语句。
normally think of an if statement
as just an if statement.
但现在我要看一个 if 语句的全部内容
But now I have to look through the entire
contents of an if statement to figure out
如果里面有一个允许的关键词并确定这是否也是一个范围
if there's a let keyword in it and
figure out if that's also a scope.
如果是范围我得更仔细地考虑我的行动
And if it is a scope I have to be more
careful about what I move around and
我能把它放在哪里
where I can put what.
所以我不是那种隐含劫持事件的大粉丝
So I'm not a big fan of that whole
implicit hijacking thing but
我是一个能够执行我们已经发出信号的粉丝
I am a fan of being able to enforce
the thing that we were already signaling
我想让这件事成为当地的事
which is, I want this thing to be local.
那么，这个全新的东西呢 ?
So what about this whole
let is the new var thing?
我肯定你以前听过
I'm sure you've heard this before,
事实上已经被替换成了新的 let了
as a matter of fact that's been replaced
even with const is the new let.
确实有 T 恤
There were literally T-Shirts made, and
被一些 TC39 年的成员所戴的背所戴的，让我们是新的 var。
worn by some members of TC39 years
back that said, let is the new var.
这是个横幅
This was a banner.
有一个 TC39 会员的博客帖子说，只要做个全球性的发现
And there was a blog post by a TC39 member
that said, just do a global find and
替换您的程序，并将所有出现的值替换为带有 let的变量。
replace on your program and replace
all occurrences with var with a let.
这真是个愚蠢的建议
That is an enormously
stupid piece of advice.
请不要这样做。
Please do not do that.
这主意糟透了
It's a terrible idea.
不仅你几乎肯定会制造虫子
Not only are you almost
certainly to create bugs, but
最重要的是你滥用了那个功能
importantly than that,
you're misusing that feature.
根据你从我这里看到的一切
Consistent with everything you've
already seen from me in this course,
我要告诉你这不仅仅是一个全面的
I'm gonna tell you that let is
not just some across-the-board
替换 var 关键字。
replacement of the var keyword.
但它是我们应该添加到现有用途的附加工具
But it is an additional tool that we
should add on to our existing usage
这意味着仍有使用 var 关键字的原因。
which means that there are still
reasons to use the var keyword.
与我的同龄人相比，这种情况也同样有争议或不寻常。
And that is similarly controversial or
unusual compared to my peers who
会告诉你永远永远不会再使用 " var " 关键字
would tell you never, ever,
ever use the var keyword ever again.
我会一直告诉你瓦尔的关键词是有目的的
And I'm gonna keep telling you
the var keyword has purpose.
举个例子。
Here's an example.
在这个代码中，我们有两个 vars。
In this code, we have two vars.
我们有个在循环的变量
We have a var that's on a for loop, and
我们有一个可以在整个功能上使用的变量
we have a var that's essentially being
used across the entire function.